Guide to the Polytechnic and New York University Course Materials RG.032
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Polytechnic and New York University Course Materials
1947-1983
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Guggenheimer, Heinrich W. (Heinrich Walter)
Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Department of Chemistry.
RG.032
34
4.5 Linear Feet
Arrangement
Course materials are arranged by department, then by course or seminar series.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains course materials from the Chemistry Department in polymer science and organic chemistry, and from the Mathematics Department in linear algebra. The Chemistry Department course materials span the 1940s - 1960s. The Mathematics Department materials are from the early 1980s.
Biographical / Historical
The course materials and seminar series in this collection contain insight into teachings at Polytechnic from the 1940s-1980s. Notable professors papers and course materials, such as chemical engineer Herbert Morawetz and mathematician Heinrich Guggenhiemer, are included in this collection.
The course materials were transferred from departments to the library's circulating collection in the 1970s and 1980s. They were transferred from the circulating collection to the archives in 2015.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Course materials; Polytechnic Institute of New York. Mathematics Department.
- Series I: Chemistry Department, 13188
  - Subseries A: Polymer Seminars, 13189
    - Volume XI, 1961 Fall - 1962 Spring; 13190 (Item 1)
    - Volume XIII, 1963 Fall - 1964 Spring; 13191 (Item 2)
    - Volume XIV, 1964 Fall - 1965 Spring; 13192 (Item 3)
    - Volume XV, 1965 Fall - 1966 Spring; 13193 (Item 4)
    - Volume XVI Fall, 1966 Fall; 13194 (Item 5)
    - Volume XVI Spring, 1967 Spring; 13195 (Item 6)
    - Volume XVII Fall, 1967 Fall; 13196 (Item 7)
    - Volume XVII Spring, 1968 Spring; 13197 (Item 8)
    - Volume XVIII, 1968 Fall - 1969 Spring; 13198 (Item 9)
    - Volume XIX, 1969 Fall - 1970 Spring; 13199 (Item 10)
  - Subseries B: Organic Seminar Topics, 13200
    - Fall 1947 - Spring 1948, 1947-1948; 13201 (Item 1)
    - Fall 1948 - Spring 1949, 1948-1949; 13202 (Item 2)
    - Fall 1949 - Spring 1950, 1949-1950; 13203 (Item 3)
    - Fall 1950 - Spring 1951, 1950-1951; 13204 (Item 4)
    - Fall 1951 - Spring 1952, 1951-1952; 13205 (Item 5)
    - Fall 1952, 13210 (Item 6)
    - Spring 1953, 13206 (Item 7)
    - Fall 1953, 13207 (Item 8)
    - Spring 1954, 13211 (Item 9)
    - Fall 1954, 13208 (Item 10)
    - Spring 1955, 13209 (Item 11)
    - Fall 1955, 13212 (Item 12)
    - Spring 1956, 13214 (Item 13)
    - Fall 1956, 13213 (Item 14)
    - Spring 1957, 13215 (Item 15)
    - Fall 1957, 13216 (Item 16)
    - Fall 1958, 13217 (Item 17)
    - Spring 1959, 13218 (Item 18)
    - Fall 1959, 13219 (Item 19)
    - Spring 1960, 13220 (Item 20)
    - Fall 1960, 13221 (Item 21)
    - Spring 1961, 13222 (Item 22)
    - Fall 1961, 13223 (Item 23)
    - Spring 1962, 13224 (Item 24)
    - Fall 1962, 13225 (Item 25)
    - Spring 1963, 13226 (Item 26)
    - Fall 1963 - Spring 1964, 1963-1964; 13227 (Item 27)
    - Fall 1964 - Spring 1965, 1964-1965; 13228 (Item 28)
    - Fall 1965 - Spring 1966, 1965-1966; 13229 (Item 29)
    - Fall 1966, 13230 (Item 30)
    - Spring 1967, 13231 (Item 31)
    - Fall 1967, 13232 (Item 32)
    - Spring 1968, 13233 (Item 33)
- Series II: Electrical Engineering Department, 13247
  - Propagation of Electromagnetic Waves: Lectures by Dr. R.K. Luneburg, 1947-1948; 13248 (Item 34)
  - Electromagnetic Theory: Lecture notes by Charles A. Hachemeister, Volume I, 1962-1964; 13249 (Item 35)
  - Electromagnetic Theory: Lecture notes by Charles A. Hachemeister, Volume II, 1962-1964; 13250 (Item 36)
- Series III: Mathematics Department, 13234
  - Linear Algebra and Differential Equations (MA 838), H. Guggenheimer, 1981; 13236 (Item 37)
  - Linear Algebra, H. Guggenheimer, 1983; 13235 (Item 38)